rosslaregolf.com 2019-05-12

# Privacy Policy - Rosslare Golf Club

## Privacy Policy

We, in Rosslare Golf Club, understand that privacy is very important to you, and we are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This policy, and any other documents referred to in it, sets out the basis on which any personal data we hold about you will be processed by us. The Data Protection Act (the Act) contains rules designed to protect your privacy. We are registered as a data controller for the purpose of the Act and must comply with the Act.

Personal data means any information that we hold, or are likely to hold, relating to an identified or identifiable living individual. In practice, this means personal information we hold about our members and users of our Website.

#### **1\. Information we may collect from you**

When you join or visit our Club we collect only the information required from you to be able to fulfil our contractual obligations. For example, this may include the information you provide us on registration as a member and a record of any correspondence you have with us. We may also collect further information through our website which allows us to contact you regarding events and offers at the Club. All information that we collect about you will be kept confidential with the following exceptions:

  * Information stored in the Members’ Area will be available for other members to use in accordance with the Acceptable Use Policy. You can withdraw your consent to this use of your information at any time by contacting us.
  * if disclosure is required or permitted by law;

The type of personal Information we collect from you may include all or some of the following:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email address
  * Telephone number
  * Handicap
  * Previous Clubs
  * Payment card details (for one time use only and will not be kept on file)
  * Responses to competition and promotion entries

#### **2\. How we use your personal information**

We collect and process this information in order to help us to better understand the needs and interests of our members and visitors and in order to fulfil our contractual obligations with you. We will process your personal information to provide club services to members including:

  * Sharing your information with internal/external processors:

Internal:

  * Membership Administration system i.e. SmartClub
  * Competition Card checkers
  * Staff
  * Team Captains

External:

  * BRS Booking system
  * Handicap Master
  * Golfnet
  * GUI/ILGU
  * Mail Delivery facilitator
  * Club Professional
  * Club Caterers

  * to provide you with information relating to the club or associated events;
  * to tailor the functionality/presentation of the Website and to make improvements thereto;

Your personal data is controlled internally by the Data Protection Officer (identified below) who adheres to the Club’s internal data protection policies and procedures

#### **3\. Where we store your personal information**

We will store the data that we collect about you on our secure servers which are password protected.

We do our best to protect your personal information but unfortunately the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure.

#### **4\. Your rights**

You have the right

  * to be kept informed
  * to access the information we hold about you.
  * to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes
  * to have mistakes in data held rectified at your request
  * to have certain information deleted
  * to data portability i.e. information must be provided in easy to read format eg Word, Excel
  * not to be subjected to profiling i.e. decisions made about your interests/preferences by others

#### 5. **Marketing**

In no circumstances will your personal information be used by us for direct or indirect marketing purposes other than that associated with the Club. From time to time our website may contain links to sites operated by third parties. Please note that if you follow one of these links you will leave our website and this Privacy Policy will not apply,

#### **6.CCTV**

The Club operates a recorded CCTV security system to protect the interests of our members and the Club. There are notices to this effect around the premises. There is no CCTV in the locker rooms or toilet areas.

#### **7.Cookies**

A cookie is a text only file which we transfer to your computer when you visit our website. Cookies do not store financial or personal information. WE use cookies to better understand the navigation of visitors to our website. You will be asked to consent to use cookies the first time you visit the website by clicking accept.  We do not exchange cookies with any third party or external data suppliers.

More information about cookies is available on www.aboutcookies.org

#### **8.General Consent as Parent or Guardian**

When you have provided information in respect of a Junior Member, you confirm that:

  * they have appointed you to act for them and that you are legally entitled to do so
  * you consent to the processing of their personal data
  * to receive on their behalf any data protection notices from the Club

#### **9.Changes to our privacy policy**

We keep our Privacy Policy will be under regular review. Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page, in the locker-rooms and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. We recommend that you regularly check for any updates or changes made to this privacy policy.

#### **10\. Contact**

If you have any enquiries about this notice, please email

who is the Data Protection Officer (DPO) for the purposes of GDPR

**This privacy policy was last updated on 15/06/2018**
